[Music]
welcome back well let's get uh straight
to the next Management on the show which
is IC Lombard it reported a mix set of
numbers to discuss what went on in the
past quarter whats the be ahead we have
the Company CFO and chief risk officer
Mr gopal balachandra who joins us on the
show hi gopal thanks a lot for joining
in well though the premium growth has
been strong you're actually are
underwriting loss only in increase by
around 8% so what's the strategy to
improve the underwriting performance and
what could be the kind of improvement we
expect on a sequential basis for the
remain of this
fiscal just to kind of refresh I would
only say that uh the more the businesses
grow given the fact that the earnings as
you rightly mentioned happens over the
contract period of insurance whereas the
costs are front loaded so to that extent
when you look at it from an absolute
underwriting outcome in times of grow
obviously you see you'll obviously see
that number slightly showing an elevated
outcome and that's exactly how it has
played out even for us but I think the
larger thing that I would keep saying is
a better number to look at is more the
combined ratio outcome and there if you
would have seen let's say for quarter
one of last year we were roughly at
about
103.8 uh in that range and the current
quarter has been about
12.3% um and if you look at and that's
where we get a lot of uh uh positive
from given the fact that there has been
an improvement in both growth in
revenues I think even equally the loss
ratios have been largely maintained and
the fact that the expense of management
has been within the regulatory
stipulations that has been laid out uh
so I think which is where if you look at
the combined ratio trajectory I think
that's looking very well for us in line
with what we have been talking to the
market as well and for the exit of
quarter 4 of fi25 we have spoken about a
combin ratio exit of about 101.5 so if
you look at in that context I think
directionally for as the combin ratio
trajectory is moving in that direction
as I said aided by uh renewed growth
momentum obviously a lot of focus on the
loss experience and more importantly
efficiency and productivity in the way
we are running our operations but from
an absolute underwriting outcome given
the fact that the expenses are taken up
front whereas the earnings of Premium
happen over a period of the contract of
insurance so the combin ratio has
improved to 102.3 versus 103.8 which
segments uh saw the biggest Improvement
this time in terms of combined ratio and
what's the FY 25 Target on the combined
ratio also what will that Journey look
like quarter on quarter
now so again if you were to put that in
the context of the market I think if you
look at the market is as I said still
elevated at an aggregate level as 102
112 within that I think if you look at
motor as a category which by far is of
course the second largest to the
industry revenues that has obviously
seen some improvement from 121% to let's
say 118 but it is still elevated now
obviously the trajectory that motor
combin ratio takes and the industry
combin ratio takes is something that we
will very very closely watch for but at
this point of time I will take the
second question first of yours in terms
of how do we see the exit of uh combined
ratios for Isis Lumar towards end of
fi25 at this point of time you're
sticking to the process that we have
spoken to the market which is as I said
try to get to a combin of
10.5% by exit of quarter 4 fi25 but this
obviously is in the context of how the
market environment plays out and that's
something that we will very very closely
watch out for your first point on where
have we seen the improvements in the
combined ratios I think as I said it's
been all around I think in general for
us we have been able to see an
improvement in our combined ratios on
Commercial lines even for us motor I
think the combined ratio improved
relative to the last uh year and even on
the health side I think on the corporate
Health specifically given the fact that
we able to win Accounts at our price
again I think the combin ratios have
been positive on retail health I think
at this point of time given that we are
making those investments in expensive
distribution obviously the combined
ratios for the time that we continue to
make these Investments the combined ises
will stay elevated but what we are happy
about is the fact that it is running at
a loss experience that we are
comfortable
with I got it gopal now loss ratios in
health segment spiked to
83.6% as compared to
78.7% was it because of individual or
the group segment and what would be the
target to reduce the loss ratios in the
health business too both retail and
group if you could detail that out for
us again as we kind of put out even as a
part of the earning call on the health
side again if you look at for one
specifically of this period I think what
we have seen is possibly some elevated
increase in frequency of
claims and obviously to some extent also
an increase in the average claims cost
as well uh but that's something that we
will watch for water to in general in
general for health is slightly elevated
consequent to the monsoon season so
therefore we do see some increased
incidences of claim but having said that
I think for the rest of the year in so
far as both the segments that you kind
of talked about whether it is corporate
health or whether it is retail health I
think the loss ratios range that we're
comfortable on the corporate side is
generally in the range of about 94 to
95% and on the retail side I think we're
comfortable operating at a loss ratio of
about close to 70% uh so the good news
is I think the kind of the portfolio
book that we're building up possibly
gives us a confidence that we should be
able to end the year at those levels of
loss ratio
ranges all right gopal for health growth
in the premium for retail SE M moderated
whereas the employer employee was strong
what's the Management's intention to
grow retail or the employer employee and
what share do you see retail and group
by the end of this
fiscal uh so if you ask us uh Health as
a category is a preferred segment for us
now that obviously kind of includes both
uh as you rightly mentioned employer
employee as well as let's say the retail
Health now when it comes to employer
employee uh effectively as what I was
talking about
in the past there have been challenges
from a market perspective the market
because the loss issues for that segment
was significantly elevated now obviously
thank thanks to some of the improvements
in pricing that the market has seen
which is why I talked about the fact
that for is Lombard we have been able to
win Accounts at a price at which we are
comfortable with and hence that gives us
the confidence that we should be able to
run that book broadly at a loss rati
range anywhere between 94 95% but if you
ask us is that an area of thrust of
course it's an area of thrust given the
fact that there is an improved pricing
sentiment that is playing out in the
market so H to that extent for Isa
that's a very very preferred segment on
the retail side again as I mentioned
that's an area where currently we are in
an expensive mode and thankfully the way
we have been kind of expanding the book
as I said again is leading to a loss
outcome broadly at a loss ratio range
that we comfortable with which is at
about
70% are you looking to take any price
hikes in your health
portfolio ask ask us I think at this
point of time we believe we are fairly
priced in terms of the uh health
insurance offerings that we have
particularly on the retail side given
the fact that that's a solution that we
have kind of uh recently put into
practice but but having said that
obviously that's something that we will
keep looking for in terms of the loss
outcome of the portfolio that we're
underwriting at this point of time as I
indicated I think the the loss ratio
range that we are largely comfortable
with is operating on the retail side at
about 70% and to that extent We Believe
I think we are kind of fairly priced but
obviously we will see the experiences
play out over the subsequent quarters
and should there be a need for us to do
any kind of a price revision obviously
we will come back and talk to the market
specifically about that but more
importantly I think if you ask us a
larger Focus for us is also on trying to
manage the cost of claims and to that
extent I think there's a lot of focus
that company has been kind of doing in
order to make sure that we are also able
to keep the cost of claims under check
uh got it now uh you know loss ratio in
the motor segment has also come down is
down to about 80
66.8% uh and in the Property and
Casualty segment is down to about
74.9 uh Is there further scope as you
see it uh to reduce loss ratios in these
segments and to what
point on motor as a category I think
generally we are comfortable running at
a loss ratio range between 65 to 67%
and within that we have talked about on
motor own damage a loss ratio range of
between 60 to 65 and on third party a
loss ratio range between 65 to 70% so
that's in motor as a category on the
property and casuality which is largely
let's say the commercial lines I think
again we would keep saying that I think
it's very difficult to look at it from a
quarter to quarter basis primarily
because some of these catastrophic
events can have an impact in the loss
numbers for that particular given
quarter so let's say for example in a
given quarter you see two three flood
events or catastrophic events but but
naturally given the nature of the
business obviously we will see some
losses but when you look at it over a
longer period of time which will kind of
play out in terms of averages I think at
this point of Time commercial lines for
us has been one of the best Roe
generating uh segments of businesses as
well and that's a segment where for Isis
Lombard we have been continuing to
increase market share as well and hence
therefore to summarize
both on motor and the commercial lines
the loss ratios range over periods are
kind of well within the range that tus
Lumbard is com comfortable operating
at gopal we'll leave it there thank you
very much for joining us and running us
through all of that detail and a fair
bit of guidance as well as you see it
thank you for your time